[al:全新版大学英语（第二版）听说教程4]
[ti:Unit12 PartB]
[ar:上海外语教育出版社]
[by:上海外语教育出版社]
[00:00.00]Unit 12  Reality TV
[00:07.14]Part B
[00:09.26]Listening Tasks
[00:11.91]A Passage
[00:14.36]Reality TV Around the Globe
[00:18.19]Exercise 1
[00:20.57]Listen to the passage and choose the right answers to the questions you hear.
[00:26.83]Reality TV shows have taken the world by storm.
[00:30.58]Survivor, Big Brother and other shows have drawn hundreds of
[00:34.29]millions of viewers to the screen.
[00:37.30]It was in Europe that all this started.
[00:40.53]The first series of this kind of show was called Expedition Robinson.
[00:45.24]It was shown in Sweden in 1997, and was soon a hit.
[00:50.12]That show placed young people in faraway places to compete against each other.
[00:55.09]The finale of the show was watched by half the Swedish population,
[00:58.98]making it one of the most popular programs in the country's history.
[01:03.47]Its success alerted TV bosses around the world
[01:06.83]to the potential of watching ordinary people try hard to survive in the wilderness.
[01:12.63]Officials at CBS Broadcasting Inc.
[01:15.11]in the United States decided to produce their own version of the show.
[01:20.03]This is how Survivor came into existence.
[01:23.27]They chose 16 Americans of different ages
[01:25.77]and races to live on a South Pacific island in May 2000.
[01:30.91]The contestants on the island had some real problems to tackle.
[01:34.99]One of them was food, as they had to find and cook their own food.
[01:39.47]Sometimes, they were even forced to catch and eat rats and worms.
[01:44.59]Experts say that Survivor is popular
[01:47.16]because television viewers like to watch people in real situations
[01:51.05]where the final result is unknown.
[01:53.78]Viewers also like to watch other people's struggles
[01:56.61]and problems because it makes them feel better about their own lives.
[02:01.90]Big Brother started in Holland.
[02:04.26]Nine volunteers took part in the show
[02:06.85]and were filmed 24 hours a day for 100 days.
[02:10.70]It became one of Holland's top-rated shows within a month,
[02:14.38]and drew 15 million viewers for its climax on New Year's Eve 1999.
[02:20.55]And its success prompted TV stations around the world to buy the idea.
[02:25.59]Two months after the appearance of Survivor,
[02:28.25]the American version of Big Brother was aired in the United States,
[02:32.35]involving ten participants.
[02:34.81]Winners of the two shows can walk away with a lot of money.
[02:38.54]Survivor's prize was $1 million,
[02:41.34]whereas Big Brother contestants could win $500,000,
[02:45.34]and Survivor triumphed in the ratings.
[02:48.63]Britain started its reality shows later than
[02:50.82]some of its European and American counterparts.
[02:54.14]In fact, Survivor was dreamed up by a Briton named Charlie Parsons,
[02:58.95]but the idea was not picked up in his home country
[03:01.86]until it had been a success in Scandinavia and America.
[03:07.89]Questions
[03:10.15]1. Which of the following reality TV shows are mentioned in the passage?
[03:17.79]2. Who are the performers in reality TV shows?
[03:24.29]3. What is the essence of a reality TV show?
[03:30.62]4. Which of the following is true about Survivor
[03:34.12]and Big Brother when shown in different countries?
[03:39.80]5. What nationality is Charlie Parsons,
[03:44.23]who first got the idea of the reality TV show Survivor?
[03:50.17]6. What occurred to TV bosses around the globe
[03:53.96]after the success of the first series of Survivor?
[03:59.96]Exercise 2
[04:02.69]Listen to the passage again and write down answers to the questions you hear.
[04:09.27]Reality TV shows have taken the world by storm.
[04:13.12]Survivor, Big Brother and other shows have drawn hundreds of
[04:16.66]millions of viewers to the screen.
[04:19.18]It was in Europe that all this started.
[04:22.20]The first series of this kind of show was called Expedition Robinson.
[04:26.92]It was shown in Sweden in 1997, and was soon a hit.
[04:31.52]That show placed young people in faraway places to compete against each other.
[04:36.75]The finale of the show was watched by half the Swedish population,
[04:40.74]making it one of the most popular programs in the country's history.
[04:45.26]Its success alerted TV bosses around the world
[04:48.75]to the potential of watching ordinary people try hard to survive in the wilderness.
[04:54.46]Officials at CBS Broadcasting Inc.
[04:57.11]in the United States decided to produce their own version of the show.
[05:01.66]This is how Survivor came into existence.
[05:05.00]They chose 16 Americans of different ages
[05:07.47]and races to live on a South Pacific island in May 2000.
[05:12.67]The contestants on the island had some real problems to tackle.
[05:17.01]One of them was food, as they had to find and cook their own food.
[05:21.21]Sometimes, they were even forced to catch and eat rats and worms.
[05:26.33]Experts say that Survivor is popular
[05:28.75]because television viewers like to watch people in real situations
[05:32.39]where the final result is unknown.
[05:35.58]Viewers also like to watch other people's struggles
[05:38.10]and problems because it makes them feel better about their own lives.
[05:43.80]Big Brother started in Holland.
[05:46.15]Nine volunteers took part in the show
[05:48.62]and were filmed 24 hours a day for 100 days.
[05:52.46]It became one of Holland's top-rated shows within a month,
[05:55.99]and drew 15 million viewers for its climax on New Year's Eve 1999.
[06:02.40]And its success prompted TV stations around the world to buy the idea.
[06:07.48]Two months after the appearance of Survivor,
[06:10.01]the American version of Big Brother was aired in the United States,
[06:13.89]involving ten participants.
[06:16.52]Winners of the two shows can walk away with a lot of money.
[06:19.92]Survivor's prize was $1 million,
[06:22.82]whereas Big Brother contestants could win $500,000,
[06:26.90]and Survivor triumphed in the ratings.
[06:30.30]Britain started its reality shows later than
[06:32.84]some of its European and American counterparts.
[06:35.79]In fact, Survivor was dreamed up by a Briton named Charlie Parsons,
[06:40.34]but the idea was not picked up in his home country
[06:43.48]until it had been a success in Scandinavia and America.
[06:49.72]Questions
[06:51.56]1. Where and when did reality TV shows originate?
[06:58.49]2. Where and when was Survivor filmed by CBS?
[07:05.88]3. What was one of the practical problems the contestants had to face in Survivor?
[07:13.77]4. How many volunteers took part in the show Big Brother in Holland?
[07:20.31]In what way and for how long were they filmed?
[07:25.82]5. When did Big Brother reach its finale in Holland?
[07:32.13]6. How much was the prize money for the winner of Survivor
[07:35.60]and Big Brother respectively?
[07:40.51]7. Of the two shows, which has comparatively fewer viewers?
[07:47.32]Speaking Tasks
[07:49.81]Pair Work
[07:51.85]A. Reflections on the text
[07:55.36]You have just heard a passage about reality TV shows.
[07:59.45]What do you think of them?
[08:00.99]How different are they from ordinary shows on television?
[08:04.78]Why do you think they are so popular?
[08:07.22]Exchange views with your partner.
[08:09.46]You may mention the following points in your discussion.
[08:12.85]○ the making of a reality TV show
[08:16.32]○ the selection of contestants
[08:19.04]○ the temptation of money and fame
[08:22.85]○ the element of suspense
[08:26.42]B. Debating — Arguments for or against reality TV shows
[08:33.51]A Sample
[08:35.14]Survivor and Big Brother have attracted countless viewers.
[08:38.89]However, some people have voiced strong objections to them.
[08:42.91]What's your opinion?
[08:44.52]Express and defend your views from the perspectives given below.
[08:49.84]Topic: Should reality TV shows be encouraged?
[08:54.92]Perspectives:
[08:56.54]1. From the perspective of a viewer (positive)
[09:02.14]2. From the perspective of another viewer (negative)
[09:08.15]Possible Arguments (for reference)
[09:12.26]From the perspective of a viewer (positive)
[09:16.76]I think reality TV provides great entertainment
[09:20.14]and should therefore be encouraged.
[09:22.68]Television has never been so close to common people,
[09:25.52]nor has it been so popular with ordinary viewers.
[09:28.86]I think it is great fun to watch people just like ourselves
[09:31.98]on TV display their intelligence
[09:35.19]and courage in solving all kinds of problems.
[09:39.21]As for the money element,
[09:40.65]I can see nothing wrong with the big prize.
[09:43.18]What about the lottery prize?
[09:45.08]Compared with lucky lottery winners,
[09:47.29]the show winners' prizes are hard-earned.
[09:50.04]They have to go through all sorts of difficulties
[09:52.42]before they can have a remote chance of winning the prize money.
[09:56.38]What is still more worthy of our admiration is their attitude toward the money
[10:00.76]they've won.
[10:01.89]Here are some moving stories about how some winners spent their prize money.
[10:06.05]One winner pledged to give his £70,000 winnings to a friend
[10:10.83]who needed a vital operation.
[10:13.07]Another used the money to take his friends on holiday.
[10:16.14]Still another winner, a guitarist,
[10:19.03]declared he would spend the money on his musical career.
[10:22.59]And a weeklong celebrity version of Big Brother raised 500,000 pounds for charity.
[10:30.04]How can we say that reality TV shows are only doing harm to society?
[10:34.56]The competitions in the shows,
[10:36.95]though intense, are carried out according to the rules of the game,
[10:40.97]which are fair to all participants.
[10:43.27]They are no different from other contests we see on TV.
[10:47.02]So why single out reality TV for blame?
[10:50.72]Something so much favored by the audience surely has something positive in it.
[10:54.97]I'd like to see more and even better reality TV shows in the future.
[11:01.64]From the perspective of another viewer (negative)
[11:06.20]I don't think I can agree with the view just expressed.
[11:09.75]There is no doubting reality TV shows have created a sensation.
[11:14.72]They have caused a big stir wherever they are shown.
[11:18.14]However, I think this type of show should not be encouraged.
[11:23.02]There is a very strong element of material incentive in it.
[11:27.26]People in the shows compete against each other only for money.
[11:31.78]Since it is a large amount of money,
[11:33.88]each contestant tries to defeat others by every means.
[11:38.22]Money stirs up greed and the fierce competition nurtures selfishness.
[11:43.72]These shows tend to bring out the worst side of human nature.
[11:47.69]Moreover, the behavior of the contestants may also affect viewers,
[11:52.21]especially young viewers, who may become money-centered as well.
[11:58.03]So such shows are doing more harm than good to society.
[12:02.32]It is just as the French protesters stated on their placard,
[12:06.61]"With trash TV people turn into idiots." I quite agree.
[12:12.52]These shows are also doing harm to the contestants themselves.
[12:17.38]Stories are being circulated about
[12:19.49]what happened to them after they left the stage.
[12:22.29]To some of them,
[12:23.38]the party is over and troubles come along.
[12:26.68]A group of former contestants in the UK
[12:29.16]talked about suffering from emotional scarring.
[12:33.04]Others complained that their reputation
[12:35.03]and careers were harmed by the scenes
[12:36.92]that appeared to reveal a nasty side of their character.
[12:41.30]As these shows are of little benefit to us all,
[12:44.86]why should we let them take so much air time on TV?
[12:48.61]*****      *****      *****      *****
[12:50.27]Now use the above sample as your model
[12:52.97]and carry on similar activities with your partner.

