[al:全新版大学英语（第二版）听说教程3]
[ti:Unit10 PartB]
[ar:上海外语教育出版社]
[by:上海外语教育出版社]
[00:00.00]Unit 10  The Cinema
[00:05.52]Part B
[00:08.27]Listening Tasks
[00:10.44]Passage 1
[00:12.16]Popcorn and the British Cinema Industry
[00:16.41]Exercise 1
[00:19.21]Listen to the recording and choose the right answers to the questions you hear.
[00:26.53]In the golden fields of Kansas, corn is growing very well.
[00:31.64]Britain's biggest cinema success is under production.
[00:35.62]Although there are no stars, no special effects, no publicity,
[00:40.54]it is still guaranteed to make more money than all but the biggest hit movies.
[00:46.42]What is it? Popcorn.
[00:48.68]Last year,
[00:49.95]cinema popcorn sales in the UK and Ireland made ￡20 million plus,
[00:55.68]way ahead of most films.
[00:57.90]Only a handful of extremely successful movies could beat it.
[01:02.67]If it were not for popcorn,
[01:05.16]soft drinks and ice cream,
[01:07.24]British cinema would be as dead as the music hall.
[01:10.81]A recent survey found that every single screen
[01:14.15]in the country needed another source of income just to keep operating.
[01:19.39]Perhaps three or four films a year make money at the box office.
[01:23.19]The other films just help cinemas tick over,
[01:26.72]and pull in people to buy popcorn and sweets.
[01:29.43]Even when a cinema is showing a must-see film,
[01:34.27]the operator is working on paper-thin profits.
[01:37.43]He must fill every seat to cover the film company's costs.
[01:41.81]Film distributors regularly demand half the money taken at the box office;
[01:47.06]with big films they can charge between 69 percent
[01:50.90]and 89 percent of the takings.
[01:53.71]Cinemas still have to pay staff and running costs out of what's left.
[01:59.03]This is where popcorn and sweets come into the picture.
[02:02.97]A large carton of popcorn from a supermarket costs only a little over 90p.
[02:09.29]Cinemagoers, however, can pay up to £4 for one large helping.
[02:14.22]At one very expensive cinema in London's West End, for example,
[02:19.15]a carton costs ￡3.95.
[02:22.53]Eating popcorn while watching a movie is said to be a real pleasure.
[02:27.82]The difference between buying popcorn at a cinema  
[02:31.17]and a supermarket is just like that
[02:33.88]between buying wine in a restaurant and at an ordinary shop.
[02:37.86]It costs twice as much or more.
[02:41.56]Questions
[02:44.77]1. What is the main idea of the passage?
[02:51.73]2. What can you infer from the passage?
[02:57.79]Exercise 2
[02:59.87]Listen to the passage again and complete the following table
[03:03.53]by filling in each blank with the missing information.
[03:07.55]In the golden fields of Kansas, corn is growing very well.
[03:13.88]Britain's biggest cinema success is under production.
[03:18.35]Although there are no stars, no special effects, no publicity,
[03:23.37]it is still guaranteed to make more money than all but the biggest hit movies.
[03:29.33]What is it? Popcorn.
[03:31.75]Last year,
[03:33.79]cinema popcorn sales in the UK and Ireland made ￡20 million plus,
[03:38.08]way ahead of most films.
[03:40.98]Only a handful of extremely successful movies could beat it.
[03:45.27]If it were not for popcorn,
[03:48.61]soft drinks and ice cream,
[03:50.15]British cinema would be as dead as the music hall.
[03:53.72]A recent survey found that every single screen
[03:57.35]in the country needed another source of income just to keep operating.
[04:01.78]Perhaps three or four films a year make money at the box office.
[04:06.17]The other films just help cinemas tick over,
[04:09.74]and pull in people to buy popcorn and sweets.
[04:13.09]Even when a cinema is showing a must-see film,
[04:16.84]the operator is working on paper-thin profits.
[04:20.67]He must fill every seat to cover the film company's costs.
[04:24.96]Film distributors regularly demand half the money taken at the box office;
[04:29.94]with big films they can charge between 69 percent
[04:33.54]and 89 percent of the takings.
[04:36.98]Cinemas still have to pay staff and running costs out of what's left.
[04:42.21]This is where popcorn and sweets come into the picture.
[04:46.04]A large carton of popcorn from a supermarket costs only a little over 90p.
[04:52.45]Cinemagoers, however, can pay up to £4 for one large helping.
[04:57.33]At one very expensive cinema in London's West End, for example,
[05:01.95]a carton costs ￡3.95.
[05:05.70]Eating popcorn while watching a movie is said to be a real pleasure.
[05:10.76]The difference between buying popcorn at a cinema
[05:14.10]and a supermarket is just like that
[05:16.56]between buying wine in a restaurant and at an ordinary shop.
[05:20.90]It costs twice as much or more.
[05:26.37]Passage 2
[05:27.94]Death of the Stunt People
[05:31.96]Exercise 1
[05:34.08]Listen to the recording and choose the right answers to the questions you hear.
[05:39.69]Hollywood's true heroes are losing their jobs.
[05:44.71]Stuntmen and stuntwomen who entertained cinemagoers
[05:48.38]by falling from the sky,
[05:50.47]swimming with sharks and driving fast cars have been replaced
[05:54.81]by technology.
[05:56.30]After surviving generations of street fights, high falls,
[06:01.04]and setting fire to themselves,
[06:03.26]the people behind top actors' most exciting scenes
[06:07.29]have had nearly all their work substituted by computers.
[06:11.58]The most dangerous and costly stunts can now be achieved
[06:15.91]by mixing computer graphics with live action.
[06:19.48]In the mid-1990s there were 12,000 registered stunt people,
[06:25.00]but more than half of them had difficulty finding work.
[06:28.88]Sometimes, six or seven teams would be working on a film.
[06:33.34]Then, after a few days,
[06:35.74]the producers would come in and say, "You can go home. "
[06:39.58]The reason was simple: cost.
[06:42.70]Computer technology made it possible to create stunts
[06:46.84]which would either be too expensive or too dangerous to attempt.
[06:51.52]One example was in Mission Impossible, starring Tom Cruise.
[06:56.73]In a scene Cruise was seen flying from an exploding helicopter
[07:01.20]onto the back of a speeding train.
[07:03.82]In fact,
[07:04.95]the image of the actor was simply added onto the scene using computers.
[07:09.61]With the rise of digital technology,
[07:13.18]insurance companies became more reluctant to cover real stunts.
[07:18.28]"If they know it can be done safely with visual effects,
[07:22.49]the companies will not insure real stunts," said a veteran stunt coordinator.
[07:28.17]Many in the industry believe stunt people should develop expertise
[07:32.71]in the new technology,
[07:34.25]acting as advisers on the virtual stunts.
[07:37.05]Some, however,
[07:38.77]think that stunt people can survive in their traditional careers.
[07:42.65]They believe that audiences won't accept stunts produced
[07:46.45]by computers for too long.
[07:49.39]Questions
[07:52.91]1. Which of the statements below best sums up the main idea of the passage?
[08:02.25]2. What is the author's attitude toward stunt people?
[08:07.99]3. What can you infer from the passage?
[08:15.17]Exercise 2
[08:17.12]Listen to the recording again
[08:18.76]and complete the following list of the stunts mentioned in the recording
[08:26.02]Hollywood's true heroes are losing their jobs.
[08:29.96]Stuntmen and stuntwomen who entertained cinemagoers
[08:33.51]by falling from the sky,
[08:36.04]swimming with sharks and driving fast cars have been replaced
[08:40.47]by technology.
[08:42.00]After surviving generations of street fights, high falls,
[08:46.66]and setting fire to themselves,
[08:49.65]the people behind top actors' most exciting scenes
[08:53.29]have had nearly all their work substituted by computers.
[08:57.18]The most dangerous and costly stunts can now be achieved
[09:01.58]by mixing computer graphics with live action.
[09:05.10]In the mid-1990s there were 12,000 registered stunt people,
[09:10.62]but more than half of them had difficulty finding work.
[09:14.35]Sometimes, six or seven teams would be working on a film.
[09:18.91]Then, after a few days,
[09:21.36]the producers would come in and say, "You can go home. "
[09:25.29]The reason was simple: cost.
[09:28.82]Computer technology made it possible to create stunts
[09:32.66]which would either be too expensive or too dangerous to attempt.
[09:37.27]One example was in Mission Impossible, starring Tom Cruise.
[09:41.97]In a scene Cruise was seen flying from an exploding helicopter
[09:46.85]onto the back of a speeding train.
[09:49.43]In fact,
[09:50.74]the image of the actor was simply added onto the scene using computers.
[09:55.26]With the rise of digital technology,
[09:58.70]insurance companies became more reluctant to cover real stunts.
[10:03.53]"If they know it can be done safely with visual effects,
[10:08.05]the companies will not insure real stunts," said a veteran stunt coordinator.
[10:13.52]Many in the industry believe stunt people should develop expertise
[10:18.40]in the new technology,
[10:19.89]acting as advisers on the virtual stunts.
[10:23.06]Some, however,
[10:24.64]think that stunt people can survive in their traditional careers.
[10:28.48]They believe that audiences won't accept stunts produced
[10:32.08]by computers for too long.
[10:36.38]Speaking Tasks
[10:39.00]Pair Work
[10:40.38]Debating — Arguments for or against the view that
[10:44.99]watching a film at home is better than watching it at a cinema
[10:49.20]A  Sample
[10:51.32]Some people prefer watching a film at home
[10:55.08]while others think it is far better to watch it at a cinema.
[10:58.74]Which do you prefer?
[11:00.91]Why? Express and defend your views from the perspectives given in the card below.
[11:07.78]Topic:  Is it better to watch a film at home than at a cinema?
[11:14.88]Perspectives:
[11:16.64]1. From the perspective of a student (positive)
[11:23.15]2. From the perspective of another student (negative)
[11:29.70]Possible Arguments (for reference)
[11:34.00]From the perspective of a student (positive)
[11:38.02]I would rather watch a film at home than at a cinema.
[11:41.19]It is more relaxing and comfortable.
[11:44.08]At home, you can move about whenever you want
[11:47.38]and you can eat or drink whatever you like while watching.
[11:51.45]You can also watch it in any posture.
[11:54.30]You can lie down in bed or sit on the floor.
[11:57.42]But at a cinema,
[11:58.73]you have to sit through a film in a darkened hall among a lot of strangers.
[12:03.93]A lot of fun of film-watching comes from sharing the experience with others.
[12:08.95]Watching a film at home encourages interaction among the viewers,
[12:13.54]who are either your family or friends.
[12:15.98]You can discuss among yourselves the acting of the actors and actresses,
[12:20.77]or make guesses about the possible ending of the film.
[12:24.93]You can even laugh, cry, or curse with the characters.
[12:29.04]But at a cinema, talking is not welcome.
[12:32.48]Even if you go with a friend,
[12:34.92]you are not supposed to talk for fear you might disturb the others.
[12:39.08]What is more,
[12:40.85]watching films at home can save you money for tickets
[12:44.47]and time for traveling.
[12:46.28]From the perspective of another student (negative)
[12:52.39]I think the view just expressed is true only to a certain extent.
[12:58.54]In my opinion, watching a film at a cinema is much more enjoyable.
[13:03.29]No TV screen can compare with the big screens in cinemas.
[13:08.12]A home television set can in no way produce the same visual or audio effects.
[13:15.27]Watching a film at home may be more relaxing
[13:19.06]but you will miss a lot so far as these are concerned.
[13:23.00]With films that excel in scenery and music, you will miss a tremendous lot.
[13:29.10]In addition, new films are only shown in cinemas.
[13:33.37]If you want to watch them at home,
[13:36.00]you'll have to wait several months for their DVD versions to be released.
[13:39.96]If all your friends talk about a new film they have seen
[13:43.46]and you don't know anything about it,
[13:45.19]you will feel left out.
[13:47.00]As for the silence and darkness in a cinema,
[13:50.39]I think they help you concentrate on what is happening on the screen.
[13:54.71]Doing too many things while watching a film can be distracting.
[13:59.18]If all you want is to eat and talk,
[14:02.22]why do you have to do them while watching a film?
[14:05.65]*****      *****      *****      *****
[14:06.69]Now use the above sample as a model and discuss the following topic.
[14:11.48]You can refer to the notes provided below for ideas and vocabulary.
[14:16.45]You are also welcome to contribute ideas of your own.
[14:20.84]The notes offer the major divisions as argument and counter-argument.
