[al:全新版大学英语（第二版）听说教程4]
[ti:Unit11 PartB]
[ar:上海外语教育出版社]
[by:上海外语教育出版社]
[00:00.00]Unit 11  Opinion Polls
[00:06.73]Part B
[00:08.63]Listening Tasks
[00:11.57]A Conversation
[00:14.17]Opinion Polls
[00:16.30]Exercise 1
[00:18.47]Listen to the conversation and choose the right answers to the questions you hear.
[00:24.96]M: Do you know the thing that's always struck me as odd about opinion polls?
[00:29.01]W: What's that?
[00:30.05]M: The percentages.
[00:31.55]Like recently there was a survey about what people thought about traffic,
[00:36.03]and petrol prices, and public car parks.
[00:39.69]In some car parks it now costs something like £5 to park a car for half an hour.
[00:45.79]W: Yeah, but I don't see what you're getting at.
[00:48.91]M: What I mean is the percentages in the results.
[00:52.12]So there might be 70% of people who complained about high petrol prices,
[00:56.87]and 60% who want to see the traffic reduced,
[01:00.26]and 65% who think car park charges are too high.
[01:05.78]Does that mean that there are 35% who actually think the charges are OK
[01:10.62]and would even be prepared to pay more,
[01:13.02]and another 30% who think petrol prices are OK?
[01:17.27]I mean that's absurd.
[01:19.46]I don't know anyone who doesn't think they're too high.
[01:22.38]W: Well, actually I think we should pay more.
[01:25.32]M: Come on, you're joking.
[01:27.13]W: No, seriously. I think we should pay more for petrol,
[01:30.80]even twice as much maybe,
[01:32.34]and certainly far more for inner city car parks.
[01:35.96]M: But why?
[01:37.54]W: More taxes should be charged on petrol,
[01:39.47]I think, to discourage people from using cars,
[01:42.96]and we should have a kind of graded charging system for car parks depending on
[01:47.07]how far they are from the city center.
[01:50.37]M: What do you mean?
[01:52.04]W: Well, if you park your car quite far from the city center,
[01:55.66]then you pay a nominal amount
[01:57.52]as a kind of reward for not polluting the city center.
[02:00.95]Well, the closer you get to the center,
[02:03.04]the more you are penalized.
[02:05.07]Prices in the center should be totally prohibitive.
[02:08.01]I mean with an efficient bus
[02:09.68]or tram service there's no excuse for using cars.
[02:13.71]M: Yeah, but you can't penalize people
[02:15.84]who don't use their cars to go into town.
[02:19.05]I mean if you doubled the price of petrol,
[02:21.95]it would cost people a fortune to go anywhere,
[02:25.11]even on short trips, and especially on holidays.
[02:28.37]W: Don't use your car then. Use a train.
[02:31.31]M: Well, anyway, I still can't believe that 35% of those people
[02:35.74]who said car park charges were OK all think the same as you.
[02:40.80]W: Well, maybe that's where you are wrong.
[02:43.02]Just think about what I've said and you'll realize
[02:45.82]that perhaps it's not so stupid as it sounds.
[02:51.36]Questions
[02:53.53]1. The two speakers were talking about a survey.
[02:57.22]What was the survey about?
[03:01.29]2. What does the man find absurd about the survey?
[03:07.93]3. Which of the following best reflects the woman's view about car parking?
[03:14.96]4. Which problem is the woman most concerned about according to the conversation?
[03:22.51]5. Which of the following describes the man's attitude toward opinion polls?
[03:30.33]Exercise 2
[03:32.64]Listen to the conversation again and write down answers to the following questions.
[03:39.13]M: Do you know the thing that's always struck me as odd about opinion polls?
[03:43.65]W: What's that?
[03:44.74]M: The percentages.
[03:46.41]Like recently there was a survey about what people thought about traffic,
[03:50.66]and petrol prices, and public car parks.
[03:54.30]In some car parks it now costs something like £5 to park a car for half an hour.
[04:00.32]W: Yeah, but I don't see what you're getting at.
[04:03.53]M: What I mean is the percentages in the results.
[04:06.56]So there might be 70% of people who complained about high petrol prices,
[04:11.53]and 60% who want to see the traffic reduced,
[04:15.19]and 65% who think car park charges are too high.
[04:20.35]Does that mean that there are 35% who actually think the charges are OK
[04:25.27]and would even be prepared to pay more,
[04:27.85]and another 30% who think petrol prices are OK?
[04:31.88]I mean that's absurd.
[04:34.14]I don't know anyone who doesn't think they're too high.
[04:37.03]W: Well, actually I think we should pay more.
[04:39.96]M: Come on, you're joking.
[04:41.76]W: No, seriously. I think we should pay more for petrol,
[04:45.38]even twice as much maybe,
[04:47.05]and certainly far more for inner city car parks.
[04:50.59]M: But why?
[04:52.17]W: More taxes should be charged on petrol,
[04:54.48]I think, to discourage people from using cars,
[04:57.32]and we should have a kind of graded charging system for car parks
[05:01.09]depending on how far they are from the city center.
[05:04.98]M: What do you mean?
[05:06.61]W: Well, if you park your car quite far from the city center,
[05:10.55]then you pay a nominal amount as
[05:12.26]a kind of reward for not polluting the city center.
[05:15.61]Well, the closer you get to the center,
[05:17.33]the more you are penalized.
[05:19.72]Prices in the center should be totally prohibitive.
[05:22.80]I mean with an efficient bus
[05:24.55]or tram service there's no excuse for using cars.
[05:28.31]M: Yeah, but you can't penalize people
[05:30.35]who don't use their cars to go into town.
[05:33.61]I mean if you doubled the price of petrol,
[05:36.77]it would cost people a fortune to go anywhere,
[05:39.76]even on short trips, and especially on holidays.
[05:42.97]W: Don't use your car then. Use a train.
[05:46.00]M: Well, anyway, I still can't believe that 35% of those people
[05:50.49]who said car park charges were OK all think the same as you.
[05:55.42]W: Well, maybe that's where you are wrong.
[05:57.91]Just think about what I've said and you'll realize
[06:00.44]that perhaps it's not so stupid as it sounds.
[06:06.00]Speaking Tasks
[06:08.76]Pair Work
[06:10.57]A. Reflections on the text
[06:13.78]You have just heard a conversation
[06:15.13]in which two speakers were discussing the reliability of opinion polls.
[06:19.97]What does the man feel odd about the results of the poll?
[06:23.61]What is the woman's opinion with regard to petrol prices and car park charges?
[06:28.58]What does the conversation tell you about the functions
[06:31.23]and limitations of opinion polls?
[06:33.95]Exchange views with your partner.
[06:36.14]You may mention the following points in your discussion.
[06:39.57]○ different views held by the two speakers about certain poll results
[06:44.77]○ opinion polls reflecting highly diversified views
[06:49.20]○ poll results expressed in percentages:
[06:51.87]sometimes difficult to interpret
[06:53.77]as they fail to reveal the reasons behind people's responses to survey questions
[06:59.37]B. Describing and analyzing data in opinion polls
[07:06.07]A Sample
[07:07.96]The table below shows the results of a survey conducted by a university
[07:12.66]to evaluate the degree of student satisfaction with their academic study.
[07:17.45]A total of 1,020 undergraduate students participated in the survey.
[07:23.73]Work together with your partner
[07:25.45]and prepare a report of the survey results based on the data provided.
[07:32.27]A  Survey
[07:33.85]How satisfied are you with the quality of education at this university?
[07:39.93]Possible Description and Analysis (for reference)
[07:44.00]The results of the survey show
[07:45.64]that the vast majority of the students
[07:47.69]have high levels of satisfaction with most of the survey items
[07:51.32]regarding their academic study at the university.
[07:55.38]Nine out of ten students interviewed say
[07:58.18]they are satisfied or very satisfied with the teaching staff
[08:01.64]and 80% of them declare that they are satisfied
[08:04.95]or very satisfied with the quality of instruction in their major.
[08:09.63]In addition, most of them are also happy about the courses offered
[08:13.45]at the university and the class size relative to the type of course,
[08:18.15]which received a satisfaction rate of 85% and 81% respectively.
[08:24.52]Despite the overall positive responses,
[08:27.06]the survey results also reveal
[08:29.39]that there are areas where the need for improvement is apparent, notably,
[08:33.64]in the amount of contact with faculty outside of class.
[08:37.81]More than a third of those interviewed say
[08:40.06]they are dissatisfied or very dissatisfied.
[08:43.52]There is obviously work to be done on the part of the university
[08:46.48]to promote student-faculty interaction outside of class.
[08:50.47]Another area with a relatively low satisfaction rate concerns
[08:54.29]the amount of help the students receive in preparation for their future career.
[09:00.16]Only a little more than half of those interviewed say they are satisfied.
[09:04.37]To prepare students for their future career
[09:06.39]is one of the most important functions of a university.
[09:10.18]It seems necessary
[09:11.32]that the university make more effort to meet this need of the students.
[09:15.56]To sum up, results from the survey indicate
[09:19.00]that the overall feedback of the students about their academic study
[09:22.48]at the university is positive.
[09:25.24]There are, however, areas where improvement is called for.
[09:29.80]These findings will be useful in helping the university to move
[09:32.72]in the right direction to improve the quality of education for its students.
[09:38.87]*****      *****      *****      *****
[09:39.78]The table below shows the results of a survey conducted in another university.
[09:45.60]In this survey,
[09:46.84]students are asked whether or not they have used certain facilities
[09:50.87]and services provided by the university,
[09:53.80]and if they have, how satisfied they are with them.
[09:58.05]Use the above sample as your model
[10:00.04]and give an oral report of the survey results based on the data provided.

