[al:全新版大学英语（第二版）听说教程4]
[ti:Unit13 PartB]
[ar:上海外语教育出版社]
[by:上海外语教育出版社]
[00:00.00]Unit 13  That's Life
[00:06.34]Part B
[00:08.06]Listening Tasks
[00:10.72]A Passage
[00:12.47]Unfair Exchange
[00:16.03]Exercise 1
[00:18.25]Listen to the story and write down answers to the questions you hear.
[00:23.84]The exchange rate between South Africa's currency, the rand,
[00:27.95]and many Western currencies is quite unfair.
[00:31.97]One rand will buy fewer than ten US cents.
[00:36.25]As a South African,
[00:37.96]when I'm in London my great fear is being left holding a restaurant bill.
[00:42.60]I find myself sitting bolt upright in bed just thinking about it.
[00:47.30]I recently visited England, where I was brought up.
[00:51.04]I stayed with my sister and her husband,
[00:53.53]and one evening they suggested we eat out.
[00:56.64]I knew that the cost of dining at the sort of restaurant
[00:59.66]they wanted to go to would be very expensive.
[01:03.77]Obviously I would have to offer to pay.
[01:06.84]My brother-in-law would then, hopefully,
[01:09.37]make a counter-offer.
[01:10.99]Then the tricky part.
[01:12.63]One cannot capitulate too quickly to appear mean.
[01:16.55]On the other hand, one must not be too insistent.
[01:20.66]Under normal circumstances,
[01:23.09]when it's my turn to pay for a serious dinner,
[01:25.58]I cannot for the life of me remain indifferent.
[01:29.32]Even though I try to concentrate on the conversation,
[01:32.49]my mind is on what I could have done with all the money
[01:36.18]I am about to pay for the dinner.
[01:39.03]When, inevitably, the bill arrived, it was placed between us.
[01:43.55]We both ignored it.
[01:45.40]I was hoping my brother-in-law would snatch it.
[01:48.15]This would be a tactical advantage for me.
[01:51.59]The bill began to obsess me. It would be at least £200.
[01:57.64]In South Africa, this would allow me to dine out for a week.
[02:02.05]I realized that if the bill were nearer to my brother-in-law,
[02:05.58]he would feel some obligation to pick it up.
[02:08.55]Perhaps by placing my elbows on the table,
[02:11.53]I could secretly nudge it closer to him.
[02:14.95]Maybe I should say,
[02:16.75]"I'll handle this, if you don't mind,"
[02:18.91]and then say assertively,
[02:20.38]"Waiter! I trust you accept Central African waginkas?
[02:25.66]The present exchange rate is nine million to the pound."
[02:30.21]My brother-in-law then made an unexpected move. He left the table.
[02:35.27]I had no choice but to reach forward and,
[02:38.52]as casually as I could, unfold the bill.
[02:43.26]It was for £226.
[02:46.76]My shoes fell off just like they do when a person is hit by a bus.
[02:51.36]My sister said, "Don't worry about the bill.
[02:54.27]The owner is a business partner of ours — we eat here free."
[02:58.52]If I'd known that, I would have ordered lobster.
[03:04.43]Questions
[03:06.28]1. Where did the story take place?
[03:11.56]2. Is the speaker a native of South Africa?
[03:17.61]3. With whom did he dine out that evening?
[03:22.92]4. What bothers him whenever he is in London? Why?
[03:29.59]5. Why could he have ordered lobster that evening?
[03:35.06]Exercise 2
[03:37.13]Listen to the story again
[03:38.62]and choose the right answer to complete each of the following sentences.
[03:45.13]The exchange rate between South Africa's currency, the rand,
[03:49.24]and many Western currencies is quite unfair.
[03:53.55]One rand will buy fewer than ten US cents.
[03:57.61]As a South African,
[03:59.19]when I'm in London my great fear is being left holding a restaurant bill.
[04:03.79]I find myself sitting bolt upright in bed just thinking about it.
[04:08.67]I recently visited England, where I was brought up.
[04:12.24]I stayed with my sister and her husband,
[04:14.77]and one evening they suggested we eat out.
[04:17.88]I knew that the cost of dining at the sort of restaurant
[04:20.87]they wanted to go to would be very expensive.
[04:25.12]Obviously I would have to offer to pay.
[04:28.14]My brother-in-law would then, hopefully,
[04:30.32]make a counter-offer.
[04:32.29]Then the tricky part.
[04:33.83]One cannot capitulate too quickly to appear mean.
[04:37.39]On the other hand, one must not be too insistent.
[04:42.27]Under normal circumstances,
[04:44.30]when it's my turn to pay for a serious dinner,
[04:47.23]I cannot for the life of me remain indifferent.
[04:50.58]Even though I try to concentrate on the conversation,
[04:53.65]my mind is on what I could have done with all the money
[04:57.24]I am about to pay for the dinner.
[05:00.31]When, inevitably, the bill arrived, it was placed between us.
[05:04.85]We both ignored it.
[05:06.61]I was hoping my brother-in-law would snatch it.
[05:09.55]This would be a tactical advantage for me.
[05:12.84]The bill began to obsess me.
[05:15.93]It would be at least £200.
[05:18.86]In South Africa, this would allow me to dine out for a week.
[05:23.24]I realized that if the bill were nearer to my brother-in-law,
[05:26.81]he would feel some obligation to pick it up.
[05:29.79]Perhaps by placing my elbows on the table,
[05:32.77]I could secretly nudge it closer to him.
[05:36.11]Maybe I should say,
[05:37.65]"I'll handle this, if you don't mind,"
[05:40.13]and then say assertively,
[05:41.53]"Waiter! I trust you accept Central African waginkas?
[05:46.86]The present exchange rate is nine million to the pound."
[05:51.46]My brother-in-law then made an unexpected move.
[05:54.74]He left the table.
[05:56.46]I had no choice but to reach forward and,
[05:59.35]as casually as I could, unfold the bill.
[06:04.36]It was for £226.
[06:07.97]My shoes fell off just like they do when a person is hit by a bus.
[06:12.54]My sister said, "Don't worry about the bill.
[06:15.52]The owner is a business partner of ours — we eat here free."
[06:19.74]If I'd known that, I would have ordered lobster.
[06:24.92]Speaking Tasks
[06:27.49]Pair Work
[06:29.19]A. Reflections on the text
[06:32.98]You've just heard a story about what happened to a man on a normal day.
[06:37.40]How do you like the story?
[06:39.21]And what do you think of the man?
[06:41.51]Do you think he is stingy?
[06:43.59]Or do you think that his worries are justifiable?
[06:46.75]Exchange views with your partner.
[06:49.32]You may mention the following points in your discussion.
[06:53.16]○ the unfair exchange rate between the South African rand and the British pound
[06:59.07]○ the man's worries about eating at a restaurant in London
[07:03.09]○ his upbringing
[07:05.07]○ how he tried to handle the bill with tact
[07:08.17]○ how he poked fun at himself
[07:11.37]B. Debating — Arguments for or against going Dutch
[07:17.83]A Sample
[07:19.66]Going Dutch is not regarded a traditional practice in China.
[07:23.50]However, it is now popular with many people in our country,
[07:27.56]especially with the young.
[07:29.55]Are you for it or against it?
[07:31.76]Express and defend your views from the perspectives given below.
[07:36.95]Topic: Is it good to go Dutch when eating out with friends?
[07:43.00]Perspectives:
[07:44.99]1. From the perspective of a student (positive)
[07:50.64]2. From the perspective of another student (negative)
[07:56.50]Possible Arguments (for reference)
[07:59.84]From the perspective of a student (positive)
[08:03.50]I think it is good policy to share the cost of a meal with friends.
[08:07.74]Since we share the meal,
[08:09.19]it's only reasonable that we should share the cost.
[08:12.48]In the old days,
[08:13.66]paying bills was supposed to be the concern of men only,
[08:17.18]who had to act as generous hosts before their friends,
[08:20.47]especially lady friends, even if they were quite hard up.
[08:24.44]They could not afford to lose face in front of others.
[08:27.65]Nowadays, as most women in our country have become financially independent,
[08:32.47]they don't have to rely on men and don't expect them to pay for meals.
[08:37.27]Equality for both men and women should not be just about work opportunities
[08:42.37]but about other areas of life as well, including paying bills.
[08:46.55]Going Dutch when we eat out with friends
[08:49.48]can also save us some embarrassing situations.
[08:52.69]As students, we are basically supported by our parents
[08:56.30]and can hardly afford to treat our friends in a restaurant,
[08:59.32]let alone in an expensive one.
[09:01.67]But we really enjoy being together with our friends
[09:04.42]and it is a treat to us to have dinner together in a restaurant we like.
[09:08.57]If one person were to pay the bill,
[09:10.60]this kind of enjoyment wouldn't be possible.
[09:13.31]Going Dutch helps us solve the financial problem of eating together
[09:17.46]with friends in a restaurant.
[09:19.23]I think it is a very good idea.
[09:22.97]From the perspective of another student (negative)
[09:27.53]Nowadays some people prefer to go Dutch when they eat out with their friends.
[09:32.90]Personally, I don't favor the practice.
[09:36.01]I think friends are friends, not strangers.
[09:39.53]And friends are supposed to treat each other from time to time.
[09:43.19]We like to entertain our friends with a dinner in a good restaurant
[09:46.78]once in a while and we also like to be entertained in return.
[09:51.18]If everyone were to pay for his share of a meal,
[09:53.93]it wouldn't look like a gathering of friends,
[09:56.91]but more like a group of mere strangers
[09:58.63]who happen to share a dinner table in a dining hall.
[10:02.37]For thousands of years,
[10:04.12]our culture has taught us to be hospitable to our guests.
[10:07.99]Suppose we eat out in a restaurant with some friends,
[10:11.29]and there is no designated host or hostess. What happens?
[10:15.58]Very likely, everyone will try to snatch the restaurant bill
[10:19.50]before others in order to show hospitality.
[10:22.89]If our friends were to pay for their shares of the meal,
[10:26.59]we would feel humiliated and hurt.
[10:30.02]Even though we are only students and are far from being rich,
[10:33.77]we can take turns to treat our friends to a decent meal in a small restaurant.
[10:38.82]As one hospitable gesture is followed by another,
[10:41.67]and still another, life will be made so much more enjoyable.
[10:46.13]***** ***** ***** *****
[10:48.66]Now use the above sample as your model
[10:50.94]and carry on similar activities with your partner.
Topic: Is it a good idea to entertain guests with a large dinner?

